

# Francesc Porta Solsona

# **Game Programmer**

Barcelona, Spain

(+34) 660 57 52 39



Gamer, Dungeon Delver, Musician, Martial Artist

### HELLOI

I'm a passionate Game Developer, proficient C++ and C# programmer, with great capacity for knowledge integration and creativity. Experience working in multidisciplinar environments. Co-Founder and Solo Programmer at TeamUglyGames which will soon be releasing *Ugly*, its first award-winning title.

# ·SKILLS·







## · LANGUAGES ·

Catalan: Native Spanish: Native English: Professional working proficiency French: B1.2

PERSONAL PROJECTS

### **PORTFOLIO**

Master's Engine project

Master's Game project

GameJam Cultura Abierta

BulKak - Rock Band

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# TEAM UGLY GAMES INDIE GAME DEV

February 2022 to Present - Barcelona, Spain

Currently developing Ugly, a 2D puzzle-platformer game made with Unity and C#. Soon to be released on Steam, NSwitch and XBox.

Fully supports 12 languages, controls remapping, 3 game slots with shared settings. Features 70+ rooms with unique puzzles, 6 bosses and 2 endings.

https://store.steampowered.com/app/1983220/Ugly/

- Co-Founder and Account Administrator.
- Solo Programmer. Complete Gameplay and Tools for artists, TA and myself.
- · Audio Coordinator.
- Assistant to Game Design and Technical Art.

# UP2SMART INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGICAL SOLUTIONS DATA ANALYST & AI DEVELOPER

September 2019 to August 2021 – Tarragona, Spain

- Creation of predictive model for Medical diagnosis. Early Acromegally detection using combination of Machine Learning systems. *Python, Matlab*.
- Plan and Design different prediction techniques for an Automatic Treatment Plan Reccomendation System for Social Service Centers.

Data Engineering. Tool to automatically generate spritesheets used in Mental Illness Center in treatments analysis and optimisation. *Mysql, Python, Java*.

# 1-ONE SANTÉ ET SECURITÉ AU TRAVAIL WEB DEVELOPER

June 2015 to August 2015 - Bordeaux, France

### EDUCATION

### MASTER IN ADVANCED PROGRAMMING FOR AAA VIDEOGAMES

October 2020 to November 2021 - Barcelona, Spain

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)

Master's Project: Develop a game using our own in-house Game Engine in C++:

- <u>QA Lead:</u> Engine and Gameplay QA. Code Reviews, feature review and conflict solving. Code and project cleansing.
- <u>Engine Programmer:</u> 3D rendering pipeline using SDL, openGL and GLSL. Implementation of Bullet Physics library, ffmpeg video libary. "Helping hand" in Animation, UI and Serialization systems.
- <u>Gameplay Programmer:</u> Dialogue & Tutorials Manager, Game Controller, God Mode, Cutscenes.
- <u>Game Designer:</u> Character Backstory, Game Narrative, Game Systems (<u>GDD link</u>). Communication nexus between programmers, artists and leadership team.

### **BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

September 2014 to June 2020 - Tarragona, Spain

Universitat Rovira i Virgili (URV)

• Bachelor's degree Final Project: "Pectoral Muscle Segmentation" (<u>Paper</u> - <u>App</u>)